<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>ssl on Vikas Pogu</title>
    <link>https://vikaspogu.dev/tags/ssl/</link>
    <description>Recent content in ssl on Vikas Pogu</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>Copyright © 2021</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 10 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://vikaspogu.dev/tags/ssl/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Jenkins OpenShift OAuth SSL</title>
      <link>https://vikaspogu.dev/blog/openshift-jenkins-oauth-ssl/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vikaspogu.dev/blog/openshift-jenkins-oauth-ssl/</guid>
      <description>Jenkins SSL # Problem # I recently encountered an issue while authenticating to OpenShift Jenkins using the OpenShift OAuth plugin, where trusted certificates provided by CA aren&amp;rsquo;t included in the default JRE TrustStore.
Logs from Jenkins pod
2020-02-10 21:19:07.335+0000 [id=17] INFO o.o.j.p.o.OpenShiftOAuth2SecurityRealm#transportToUse: OpenShift OAuth got an SSL error when accessing the issuer&amp;#39;s token endpoint when using the SA certificate2020-02-10 21:19:07.348+0000 [id=17] INFO o.o.j.p.o.OpenShiftOAuth2SecurityRealm#transportToUse: OpenShift OAuth provider token endpoint failed unexpectedly using the JVMs default keystore sun.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Configuring couchbase SSL for dynamic certificates in OpenShift</title>
      <link>https://vikaspogu.dev/blog/couchbase-ssl-openshift/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vikaspogu.dev/blog/couchbase-ssl-openshift/</guid>
      <description>Couchbase SSL # Suppose you have followed dynamic creation of java keystores in OpenShift post and wondered how to use similar concepts for couchbase database and a java application. This post will help you.
Couchbase setup # Here is the couchbase documentation for configuring server-side certificates, we are interested in last few steps since OpenShift will generate key and cert by adding an annotation to the couchbase service.
Note: By adding this annotation, you can dynamically create certificates service.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
