<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>k3s on vikaspogu</title>
    <link>https://vikaspogu.dev/tags/k3s/</link>
    <description>Recent content in k3s on vikaspogu</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 16:19:29 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://vikaspogu.dev/tags/k3s/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Measure Raspberry Pi temperature using Telegraf, Influxdb, Grafana on k3s</title>
      <link>https://vikaspogu.dev/posts/raspberry-pi-temp-telegraf/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 16:19:29 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vikaspogu.dev/posts/raspberry-pi-temp-telegraf/</guid>
      <description>In my previous post, I went through k3s cluster home setup. Now, i&#39;ll show how to measure the temperature of those Raspberry Pi&#39;s using Telegraf, Influxdb, Grafana and Helm charts.
Why Telegraf? Telegraf has a plugin called exec, which can execute the commands on host machine at certain interval and parses those metrics from their output in any one of the accepted input data formats.
First, deploy influxdb time series database chart</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>k3s cluster with Raspberry-Pi, Traefik</title>
      <link>https://vikaspogu.dev/posts/kubernetes-home-cluster-traefik/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Dec 2019 13:47:10 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vikaspogu.dev/posts/kubernetes-home-cluster-traefik/</guid>
      <description>In this post, I’ll share my home setup for Rancher&#39;s k3s kubernetes cluster.
Requirements:
 I wanted the web interface to be accessible outside of my home so I could check and manage devices while away I need to manage dynamic DNS since I don’t have a static IP  Setup  Setting up a master + single node Kubernetes cluster Deploying DNS updater as a Kubernetes CronJob object Deploying Traefik as a Kubernetes Ingress Controller and configuring it to manage SSL with Let’s Encrypt  Setting up a Pi Kubernetes Cluster I followed an excellent guide written by Alex Ellis here to initialize a cluster on the master and then join a single node.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>