<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Java on vikaspogu</title>
    <link>https://vikaspogu.dev/tags/java/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Java on vikaspogu</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 14 May 2019 14:36:27 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://vikaspogu.dev/tags/java/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Debugging a Java application in OpenShift</title>
      <link>https://vikaspogu.dev/posts/debug-java-container/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 May 2019 14:36:27 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vikaspogu.dev/posts/debug-java-container/</guid>
      <description>This post will discuss debugging a JAVA application running inside a container. First, you must set the JAVA_DEBUG environment variable inside the container to true and configure port forwarding so that you can connect to your application from a remote debugger.
Note: If you are using tomcat image replace JAVA_DEBUG environment variable to DEBUG
Using the oc command, list the available deployment configurations:
$ oc get dc Set the JAVA_DEBUG environment variable in the deployment configuration of your application to true, which configures the JVM to open the port number 5005 for debugging.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Profiling a application in OpenShift container</title>
      <link>https://vikaspogu.dev/posts/javaprofiler-openshift/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vikaspogu.dev/posts/javaprofiler-openshift/</guid>
      <description>Sometimes writing code that just runs is not enough. We might want to know what goes on internally such as how memory is allocated, consequences of using one coding approach over another, implications of concurrent executions, areas to improve performance, etc. We can use profilers for this.
In this post I&amp;rsquo;ll discuss how to use YourKit-JavaProfiler inside a container.
Since my sample application is built using OpenShift S2I process and pushed into openshift internal registry, I&amp;rsquo;ll have to pull the image locally.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
