<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>grafana on vikaspogu</title>
    <link>https://vikaspogu.dev/tags/grafana/</link>
    <description>Recent content in grafana on vikaspogu</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 16:19:29 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://vikaspogu.dev/tags/grafana/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Measure Raspberry Pi temperature using Telegraf, Influxdb, Grafana on k3s</title>
      <link>https://vikaspogu.dev/posts/raspberry-pi-temp-telegraf/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 16:19:29 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vikaspogu.dev/posts/raspberry-pi-temp-telegraf/</guid>
      <description>In my previous post, I went through k3s cluster home setup. Now, i&amp;rsquo;ll show how to measure the temperature of those Raspberry Pi&amp;rsquo;s using Telegraf, Influxdb, Grafana and Helm charts.
Why Telegraf? Telegraf has a plugin called exec, which can execute the commands on host machine at certain interval and parses those metrics from their output in any one of the accepted input data formats.
First, deploy influxdb time series database chart</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spring Boot metrics with Prometheus and Grafana in OpenShift</title>
      <link>https://vikaspogu.dev/posts/springboot-metrics-grafana/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vikaspogu.dev/posts/springboot-metrics-grafana/</guid>
      <description>In this post I&amp;rsquo;ll discuss how to monitor spring boot application metrics using Prometheus and Grafana.
Prometheus Prometheus is a monitoring system which collects metrics from configured targets at given intervals.
Grafana Grafana is an open source metric analytics &amp;amp; visualization tool.
Micrometer Micrometer is a metrics instrumentation library for JVM-based applications.
Spring Boot Actuator Spring Boot Actuator helps you monitor and manage your application when it’s pushed to production. You can choose to manage and monitor your application using HTTP or JMX endpoints.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
